Sergey Kambalin

Senior Software Engineer

kambalin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sergeykambalin

Professional software engineer with over 10 years of experience specializing in the development of advanced web and mobile applications on TypeScript/JavaScript, as well as complex services and APIs on PHP/NodeJs. Always eager to grow and share my knowledge and professional experience with others. A good mentor and effective team leader.

Professional Experience

Evolution

Lead Frontend Engineer

July 2020 - present

As Lead Engineer, I am responsible for 9 frontend engineers of various seniority levels across 3 teams. I have built friendly relationships with them, helped them grow professionally, and feel comfortable in the company.

My primary responsibilities include:

- Participate in the interview process, onboard and mentor new people
- · Help people set individual goals and OKRs, track their progress and evaluate the results
- · Ensure a healthy working environment for them. Help to solve conflicts and strengthen relationships with teammates

Senior Frontend Engineer

Nov 2019 - present

- Reorganize a complex monolithic application by applying micro-frontend architecture and gradually migrating the codebase from JavaScript/CoffeeScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React + Redux
- Drive the development of cross-team UI Kit project used in all company's back-office applications
- · Designed and developed an in-house tool (CLI) to build, test, and release complex micro-frontend projects
- Led research, development, and integration of auto-testing framework on WebdriverIO
- Developed an in-game chat module, using WebSockets for real-time communication. It is used in all the company's games
- Built (hired and mentored) a very reliable frontend team of 4 engineers in three months

Technology stack:

- TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6+)
- React & Redux ecosystem, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna + Yarn Workspaces, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library

IOLA

Senior Full Stack Engineer/Architect

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

- · Architected, developed, and successfully released React Native iOS and Android applications
- Developed PWA version of the application using React Native Web, reusing more than 90% of the native versions codebase
- Organized Storybook driven development of UI components with visual regression testing using Jest and Puppeteer
- Developed micro-frontend, platform-agnostic UI Kit based on Web Components and Preact
- Architected and developed modular GraphQL server on PHP, supporting all major GraphQL features, and full support of Relay specification
- · Achieved significant performance increase of the GraphQL server by reducing DB queries using Data Loader pattern
- Implemented real-time GraphQL subscriptions on PHP using Server-Sent Events technology

Technology stack:

- TypeScript, React, React Native, React Native Web, Apollo GraphQL, Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Jest, Puppeteer, Lerna
- PHP, SlimPHP, GraphQL-PHP, DataLoaderPHP, MySQL

Klika Tech LLC

Senior Full Stack Engineer/Team Lead

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

- Developed various company projects as a full-stack JavaScript/PHP developer, including SPAs, RESTful APIs, and services
- Led a team of 3 members developing JavaScript SDK, which is used across multiple projects
- Achieved 100% test coverage of the JavaScript SDK using Mocha, Chai, and Sinon
- As a team leader, was involved in interviewing, mentoring, and onboarding activities
- Was the leader of the company's frontend community of more than 50 members

Technology stack:

- JavaScript (ES6+), React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- PHP, PHPUnit, Pheanstalk, NodeJs, Sails, Express, MySQL

Skalfa Asia LLC

Senior Full Stack Developer/Team Lead

Dec 2012 - Sep 2016

- Led architecting and development of a hybrid iOS/Android application based on Ionic Framework and SlimPHP
- Was a key developer in a team designing and developing open source website platforms: Oxwall, Skadate
- · Led development of native iOS application on Objective C for the online dating platform: Skadate

Full Stack Developer Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

• Took part in the development and optimization of a high load SaaS solution: Wall.fm

Junior Full Stack Developer

Mar 2009 - Jul 2010

• Developed various PHP/JavaScript modules for Skadate online dating platforms, including core components and add-ons

Technical Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, GraphQL, MySQL

Frameworks React, React Native, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, GraphQL-PHP, Express

Tools Webpack, Babel, Storybook, Lerna, Yarn, NPM, Composer

Tests Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library, Puppeteer, WebdriverIO, Cypress

Education

International University of Kyrgyzstan

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Bachelor of Information Technology, Software Engineer

Sep 2003 - Jun 2007

Languages

- · Russian Native proficiency
- English Professional working proficiency